# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Manager with 15 years' experience across consulting, entrepreneurial environments and multinationals. Expert in leading complex projects on time and budget, combining strategic vision with practical execution. Recognized for reliability, collaboration, and the ability to facilitate decision-making, bringing a mix of pragmatism and sophisticated analysis to both strategy and execution.

### PERSONAL DETAILS

Via delle Forze Armate, 40 - Milano

Phone: +39 320 846 0494

Email: ferrulli.walter@gmail.com

Linkedin.com/in/walter-ferrulli

Portfolio: Link

### **EDUCATION**

Università Commerciale Luigi Bocconi:

- MSC, Marketing Management
- BSc, Economics and Management

## COURSES

- Continuous self-empowerment and careercoaching journey aimed at deepening selfawareness and driving personal growth through a structured understanding of my development strengths, areas, and personality profile.
- November 2022. From entrepreneurial idea to financial modeling.
- December 2022. Negotiation: conflict, networking, and partnerships - Advanced level.

# **LANGUAGES**

English



### **SKILLS**

A solid, cross-functional personal and professional journey has allowed me to develop vision, method, and leadership. I am ready to lead digital transformation programs as Chief of Staff or Head of Project Management.

Hard Skills: Structure and organization, business-case design, data-techbusiness cross-functionality, data analysis, advanced Excel and PowerPoint.

Soft Skills: Task prioritization, critical thinking, pragmatism, attention to detail, problem solving; strong communication and active listening, reliability

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Last 10 years

#### **ALKEMY SPA - Director**

June 2022 - Ongoing

- Accountable for revenue and profitability by client. I coordinate crossfunctional teams and internal/external stakeholders, ensuring deadlines, quality, and budget compliance; promote PM culture and tools.
- I execute go-to-market and digital transformation strategies, optimizing retail, CRM, and analytics with direct impact on operations and sales.
- Key outcomes:











Profitability tool set-up

Go-to-market & controlling

manual work

saturation

Faster decision making

#### JAKALA SPA - Senior Manager

February 2020 – June 2022

- Acted as a bridge between top management and delivery, translating strategy into execution and implementing complex business initiatives.
- Directed multifaceted programs, aligning sales & marketing strategy with data & tech implementation, coordinating resources and leading multidisciplinary teams to achieve cross-functional objectives.
- Key outcomes:











Global tenders focal point

Led tech and business

Developed pricing models

Managed negotiations Managed suppliers

ESTEE LAUDER - Business Intelligence Lead

March 2016 - January 2020

Led Corporate Business Intelligence and Business Transformation projects with a transversal approach, focusing on Finance (Brand P&L, pricing models) and Retail (trade terms and margin models).